PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a collaborative professional with about 4 years of diverse experience in implementation management and research. I became passionate about Software Engineering while working at Healthcare Bluebook. My biomedical engineering background makes me strong in problem solving, data analysis, and research.

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

Nashville Software School

- Full stack web development program focusing on Javascript and React in the Front-End section and extending to C# and the .NET suite during the Back-End
- The program provides a hands on experience to programming centered around building applications in individual and group environments

University of South Carolina -Columbia, SC

- Capstone Scholar
- Philanthropy Chairman for Beta Theta Pi Fraternity Jan 2015 - Jan 2016

SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML, CSS
- Javascript
- Git/GitHub
- React
- Command Line
- Heroku
- Figma
- Mapbox

- JSON Server
- C# & .NET
- SQL Server
- ASP.NET Core
- ADO.NET
- Entity Framework
- Salesforce

CONTACT ME



durrjp1@gmail.com



(615) 627-8779

ONLINE RESOURCES



in linkedin.com/in/durrjp



durrjp.github.io



github.com/durrjp

JON DURR

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROJECTS

Zip Markets

NSS Back-End Capstone | August 2020

- Zip Markets is a housing market tracker allowing users to view single-family home statistics for over 30,0000 U.S. zip codes - zipmarkets.azurewebsites.net
- Powered by Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) Home Price Index data and Zillow Home Value Index (ZHVI) data for all home markets by zip code, and MI Economic Research and Information Center - cost of living metrics by state
- Full-stack application built using React/Javascript front-end, C# back-end, SQL Server Express database, and Firebase authentication
- Zip code map built using Mapbox API with Urbica: react-map-gl and clustering
- Database tables populated by a separate console application allowing for CSV imports, class mapping, and ADO.NET SQL insert statements - github.com/durrjp/CSVReader

Boulder Buddy

NSS Front-End Capstone | May 2020

- Boulder Buddy is a front-end app designed for rock climbers to keep track of bouldering sessions with a simple session log system, view statistics based on userinput, and follow other climbers on the app
- Built in React utilizing React hooks with full CRUD functionality
- Fully designed for mobile in mind using Figma
- App and JSON deployed via Heroku boulder-buddy.herokuapp.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

an intuitive search application allowing users to find high Healthcare Bluebook quality, "shoppable" healthcare procedures in their local area.

Client Delivery Specialist | Jan 2019 - Feb 2020

- Implementation manager for standard (500-3,000 employee) and enterprise (3,000+ employee) clients. Managed 3-7 implementations simultaneously.
- Led implementation for clients from sales hand-off to go-live date with duties including: creating project plans in Basecamp/Trello, leading biweekly/monthly meetings, and working with development team to create a custom Bluebook website for the client
- Worked collaboratively with claims and eligibility integration team to update/audit Salesforce client information to be later visualized by other Bluebook products

Account Coordinator | Oct 2017 - Dec 2018

- Implementation lead for standard clients and implementation support for enterprise
- Performed manual site testing to assist DevOps department during weeks prior to deployments
- Main point of contact for eight standard clients with duties including: scheduling/leading monthly client calls, updating clients on new products, and frequently reporting client status to senior management
- Supported and traveled for client health fairs across the country where I interacted with employees, conducted live demo's of the Bluebook App, and collected user feedback

Berg LLC a clinical-stage, Al-powered biotechnology company

Research Associate | Sep 2016 - Oct 2017

- Worked in a dynamic research setting with scientists to characterize neurological and oncologic disease targets
- Key member of project team working to characterize neurological Parkinson's Disease targets; responsible for experimentation, data analysis and interpretation, and communication with senior management
- Worked as a Protein Sciences Intern from Jun 2016 Sep 2016 before being promoted to Research Associate in Sep 2016

JON DURR

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

MORE PROJECTS

Tabloid

NSS Group Project | July 2020

- Tabloid is a media sharing app where authors have the ability to write, publish, and react to posts with a variety of tags and categories
- Full stack application built using React/Javascript front-end, C# back-end, SQL Server Express database, and Firebase authentication
- Personally responsible for developing the components to Add, Edit, Delete, and Get all Posts as well as the lead programmer for all components involving many to many relationships (ex. Tags associated with posts and subscriptions)
- Collaborated with a team of 4 utilizing pair-programming, scrum, Agile process, and GitHub workflow github.com/durrjp/tabloid-full-stack-velours

Remote-ly

NSS Group Project | April 2020

- Remote-ly is an app allowing users to plan a cross country trip to national parks around the country. The app also allows users to select nearby Restaurants, Activities, and Camp Sites to visit and add/save to their trip
- Built using Javascript with full CRUD functionality
- Utilized external API's for National Parks (nps.gov), Weather (openweathermap.org), and Directions (graphhopper.com)
- Collaborated with a team of 4 utilizing pair-programming, scrum, Agile process, and GitHub workflow github.com/durrjp/holiday-road-solar-space-sharks

ONLINE RESOURCES

in linkedin.com/in/durrjp

□ durrjp.github.io

github.com/durrjp

CONTACT ME



durrjp1@gmail.com



(615) 627-8779